Alexandre Fourmy

13 Repton Avenue TN23 3RX Ashford **0771 420 7222** alexfourmy@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Originally, I started out as a musician and a guitar teacher, and I played in a relatively busy rock band for 10 years. During my years in the band, I also worked in food retail, finance, customer service and sales either as a manager, a salesman or as a customer and support advisor.

After turning for good the music chapter of my life in May 2020, the need for a career change, creativity and learning new things led me to studying web development part-time, after work and during my weekends.

And a year later, I quit my job to study web development full time and I now plan to apply for my first role as a junior developer in early 2022.

PERSONAL

Date of Birth: 08/03/1986

Relationship: Single

Nationality: French

Post-Brexit status:

Indefinite right to remain in the UK.

Languages: French (native), English (bilingual), Spanish (intermediate) and Japanese

(beginner).

GITHUB PROFILE:

https://github.com/a4my

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded "EMEA employee of the Year" — Fender - UK

Ultralight plane pilot — Te Vakalele Club -Wallis & Futuna

2004

Obtained pilot and passenger transport licences.

INSIGHT DISCOVERY COLORS

Blue 79%

Green 57%

Red 54%

Yellow 29%

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOVOS ACCORDANCE, Brighton — *VAT Registration Representative*

November 2019 to April 2021

Support clients throughout the VAT registration process, collating all information required and liaising with European Tax Authorities and internal departments.

FENDER, East Grinstead — Customer Relationship Manager

April 2019 to October 2019

Made regular sales calls to accounts in the assigned area. Strive to achieve budgeted sales targets for allocated sales areas. Established and maintained positive working relationships with customers and potential new clients. Maintained a high level of product knowledge for the relevant product lines being sold.

FENDER, East Grinstead — Customer Sales and Support Advisor

January 2018 to March 2019

Assisted customers, District Sales Managers and retailers with enquiries related to customer service, orders, stock, product information and returns. Awarded "Employee of the Year" 2018.

EAT Ltd, London — Assistant Manager

May 2016 to December 2017

Led and managed a team from recruitment to performance reviews and training. Managed profits and losses and kept costs to a minimum whilst maximizing every sales opportunity. Interviewed, hired, coached, developed, inspired and motivated the team to deliver excellent customer service.

Burrito Bros, London — General Manager

April 2011 to April 2016

Managed and coached team members in all aspects of their role. Organised weekly stock takes, created and analysed sales reports to develop and expand the business activity.

DISTINCTION

Enjoys working alone or as part of a team

Rigorous

Meticulous

Determined

Proactive

Resilient

Natural problem solver

Details and processes oriented

Quick learner

Driven by challenges

HOBBIES

Learning new things (through documentaries or platforms such as Udemy and Skillshare, and about space, environment, economy, space and aviation).

Rugby and basketball.

Languages.

Travelling.

Gaming.

Ugam Solutions, London — *Telemarketer*

October 2010 to March 2011

Outbound calls to collect feedback and experience from clients' customers.

Monoprix, Paris — Assistant Manager

June 2008 to July 2010

Assisted General Manager in managing and coaching a team whilst using tools and reports to reach sales targets

Self-Employed, Paris — Guitar Teacher

May 2007 to june 2008

Full-time guitar teacher in the Paris region.

EDUCATION

Music Academy International, Nancy, FR— Music Business & Guitar Degree

April 2006 to April 2007

Masterclasses and training with renowned international musicians and music business actors.

Lycée de Mata'Utu, Wallis & Futuna, FR — *Baccalauréat (French A-level)*

January 2002 to December 2005

High School Diploma. Major: Management and Communication.

COURSES

Full Stack Web development — ZTM School -Online School

September 2020 to present

Mobile app and software building using JavaScript, React, Express, Node.JS, MongoDB, APIs, and PostgreSQL.

Front End Web development — UDEMY, Memo, Codeliber – Online Courses

May 2020 to present

Training on different languages and markups to build fully responsive and interactive websites such as HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, and React.

English Course — TTI School of Camden Town -London

August 20010 to September 2010

Full-time English Lessons.

Sound Engineering Bootcamp — Musique En Scène - Tours, FR

Summer 2007

Recording, mixing and mastering with Cubase SX3.

Ultralight plane pilot program— Te Vakalele Club -Wallis & Futuna

2003 to 2004

2 year training to obtain pilot and passenger transport licenses.

UDEMY COURSES

Completed— +230 hours

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-0c55c2cc-cc26-4a02-895c-7ca8b665ce14/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-471646e0-e668-4104-ba08-2ed61e59b082/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-96e3565b-ef19-4235-8078-53b0b39a7ad7/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-64349caa-23c6-4add-b46b-fea4cb93a7a7/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-403751e0-f992-466c-9658-7071e6ea6bbb/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-e99f5d57-ff28-49a2-93da-4b0991ae6e70/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-7af2b8d3-ebc9-4d89-9fc5-a771e830b127/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-197a40c6-8d91-46c2-b5c5-03aabb1db260/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-792bc806-2f8b-4cc0-8c30-881e11904404/https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-78c96ca5-69c7-4688-9c6c-7c13d9a1aa59/